It didn't look like cashing to me. When
I was watching JD redo it, it looked
completely legit.
>> No, it's legit, man. It's freaking
legit.
>> It's legit.
>> Yeah. I
think
>> best part of when you can just, you
know, critical thing, right?
Yeah, dude.
I'm not sure you all know this, but two
of the most respected hackers in the
CTBB community, Bus Factor and XSS
Doctor, are now running monthly
hackalongs on the CTBB Discord. Okay,
you've got to check this out.
ctbb.show/isord.
We find bugs almost every time we hack.
It's crazy. And and oftentimes it's not
even the people running the hackalongs.
It's the the community members that are
hacking along with us. it. You
definitely increase your chance of
finding a bug by being on these
hackalons. So, check them out.
ctv.showisord.
Join bus XSS doctor and yours truly. And
uh let's pop some bugs. All right, let's
go back to the show.
Alrighty, doc. It has been a long time
in the making. Thanks for joining us on
the pod. Um we got we're starting like
30 minutes late because we got so
distracted talking about all the
research and the fun stuff um in
advance. So, we got to bring it to the
people as well. Um, but as always, let's
start off with a bug and then we'll
we'll get into intros. So, um, you put
four here in the doc. Let's, uh, let's
start with the
>> or no, let's start with the I like that
one first.
>> I think we going to have to mute that
one. That word out that you just said.
>> That's good.
>> Thanks for having me on. I'm super
excited to be here. I've always wanted
to be on this podcast. Um, so fine,
let's talk about this bug from a um, so
I'm going to uh the the bug is uh from
let's say a a company that makes home
automation
software uh that can sometimes be
controlled by an AI.
>> Okay.
>> And that AI um is what I was hacking.
And so um actually it starts with Gret
asking me to collab and I was like
pretty excited. Every time like a big
hacker asks me to collab, I say yes and
I get really excited about it. Um, and I
and like we started hacking and like he
found something immediately, you know,
some IOR and put me on the report. So I
was like, all right, I have to like
really show up.
>> Talk about motivation, you know, dude. I
hate it when that happens.
>> Oh my god. And I was I was like kind of
busy at work, too. And I'm like, all
right, enough. Like like we got I got to
get this bug done. I'm like looking at
this particular AI and um the AI it was
is a very powerful AI. It has access to
basically everything that the user of
this has in their whole life including
if they have home automation set up it
is this particular it can just control
the house. You could just type into the
AI turn off my alarm and it will turn
off the alarm. So it's extremely
powerful. So like the first thing you
look at is I'm like if I can prompt
inject into this AI I'm like god uh for
this for this situation. So I I
obviously I look for all the parameters
look for a Q parameter. I mean a Q
parameter would be extremely silly to
have on this app. And if it was correct
we didn't have it but there was a post
message listener that you could send a
post message through this listener and
it would it would just pop up um as a
prompt injection. Now, it I think it was
meant for a Chrome extension to use.
>> Um, but
the origin check had star.isttarget.com
as as part of the origin check. So, if
you had XSS on any anything in the
entire ecosystem of this program, you
could send this post message into this
AI and control the entire their entire
life. So, I'm like, okay, like I need to
get I need to get access this. I mean,
it's a huge ecosystem. So, I I you know,
I figured there was probably XSS. I've
actually had found XSS before, but
didn't know about this gadget. So, I'm
looking around and I actually the first
thing I look at when I'm looking for XSS
is usually file upload. Um, when I'm
like looking for easier XSS, um, and so
I I actually uploaded a file to this AI
and uh and and and I could upload
arbitrary HTML and I could visit it, but
um it was an attachment. So then I'm
like I think that there are there are
like pre-production
uh domains on this on this AI. So I I go
to all the pre-production domains I
which are identical and I upload the my
HTML payload and one of them did not
have it as an attachment.
>> That is that is a good idea dude.
>> Yeah. And so I I make the bug, I submit
the bug, and I get and when I do that,
when I do the file upload, I always test
it on a guest profile to see it if it's
if it's not a self xss, right?
>> There are no login csurfs on this
>> on this target. It's extremely locked
down for login curve.f. So a selfs
cannot be escalated or I couldn't find a
way. So I I tested on the guest profile
and it pops. So I'm like, I'm good. I'm
solid. like all I have to do is send
this and it sends a post message. Um,
and I and the the setup of the of the
bug was kind of interesting because you
couldn't have the AI in the background.
You had to have it on the foreground
because for some reason it wouldn't send
the prompt in the background.
>> Um, so I Yeah, it was really weird.
Which actually kind of takes away from
the impact of the bug a little bit
because they're seeing
>> they're seeing like turn off your alarm
system, you know? I wonder if you could
I wonder if you could do the same sort
of thing we did in that hackalong that
one time though where we like popped it
up in a little box you know like
I popped in a little box and make it
made a little bit a little bit better
looking but it still looks
>> and that's what I did. I popped it up in
a little box.
>> Yeah,
>> but I didn't like that popping up in the
front thing.
>> So I looked further into it and what was
the what was it doing when you were
turning on the alarm system? There was
an API it was calling and the API had
the same cores as the post message had.
So it had access control allow origin
star.target.com with the pre-flight.
>> So I didn't even need the post message
anymore.
>> But then are you going to hit same site
same site lacks default cookies or they
same site nonexplicit? it. No, the the
off system of this program is uh at the
level of the TL T, you know, like
there's not a separate off for every
>> Oh, yeah.
>> No, no, no. Cuz you got an XSS. So,
you're saying
>> I have an XSS. Exactly. So, I didn't
even need the post message anymore. I
could just get the XSS and have it hit
this API. So,
>> I'm like thinking I'm This is the
greatest bug I've ever found in my life.
>> I submit it.
>> I'm I first thing I do is I I message
Grety because, you know, I want him to
be impressed with me. Yeah. And uh and
he is and he is impressed with me.
>> We know that he is.
>> And he is. I think around the same time
I got a message from Gret like, "Dude,
JD is God." You know, like I message
everybody about this. Everybody I know.
I I'm so excited. I think both of you
got messages from me and and Bus Factor,
everybody that I know. And about a week
later, I get that they couldn't
reproduce it. Uh
>> oh.
>> And I'm like, "Oh my god." It turns out
that that guest profile I had tested it
on, I had logged into the app on a
different window in that guest profile.
>> And it was indeed a self access.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> Yeah. So I'm like I'm like ready to die.
Like I I've never I I had told everybody
about this bug. It was the best bug I've
ever found. And so I messaged them back
like, "Listen, give me a week."
>> Mhm.
>> Please, to find another XSS, please, and
then I'll close it if you don't find it.
And they're like, "Fine." And so I'm I
am going crazy. I have AI armies out
there trying to find XSS. I have I have
everything. I'm messaging Demo. Do you
have an XSS? You're like,
>> the last dealer, you know, the dealers.
Yeah. And so on the last day I had
looked at this other AI this company had
a lot
>> and I'm like I'm just going to do this
one last time and then I'm just going to
close it and just tail between my legs.
That's the end of hacking for me
forever. And I upload I upload the same
thing on a different AI. It again is an
attachment. And I'm like, you know, I
think this also has a pre-production
>> endpoint,
but this is a little bit different, this
bug, because there was like a parameter
that said path on the bottom.
>> So like if you uploaded it to but then
it said slashuploads.
Okay,
if you uploaded HTML to slashuploads, it
would it would fail. But you could put
after the word uploads slashhello
and then it would upload anything you
wanted to slashuploadhello
whatever this MD5 something was and it
would let me upload anything I wanted
unauthenticated
>> and that was
>> nice
>> and I was unauthenticating XSS
>> and then you weren't getting attachment
disposition
>> nope on the pre-production endpoint with
that path thing I could I just visited
it was the last day of my testing and I
got the everything and I submitted
everything and it went through and
Gretney was again very impressed with
me.
>> Dude, I I love the conclusion of that
story.
>> That was what it was all about in the
end.
>> JD, you have nothing to prove, man.
You've had nothing to prove for a very
long time.
>> No, but still, you know, you're got that
IDOR and I at least I got at least I
found a fun.
>> No, I I totally get it though. I mean, I
feel the same way. Actually, I'm hacking
with Fronz and every time I hack with
Fronz and Matias, we have hacked with
Fron and Matias for years, but every
single time I hack with Fronz and
Matias, I feel the same way because
those bastards pull out like all the
vulnerabilities. Like, as soon as you
start hacking, they're like, "Oh, I just
found this." And I'm like, "What?"
>> And then I'm like, "All right, now I got
to keep up with that." So, um, yeah. No,
I totally get it. And, uh, yeah, I think
that there's a couple really good
takeaways from that story. one which is
pre-pro might allow you to bypass the
the content disposition stuff. So,
excellent excellent insight. The fact
that it worked twice in your scenario is
very interesting. And then um also
that's another really interesting thing
to check for content disposition is
uploading it to a different directory
because maybe directory specific
download rules are in place where it's
like okay if it's slash uploads then we
do it as a attachment but if it's slash
you know whatever else
>> anything else. Yeah.
>> Very nice dude. Very nice to two very
solid takeaways on
>> you're impressed too. It was totally
worth it. The whole thing was worth it.
>> What I think that's probably the world's
best XSS escalation too. like like you
know XSS2 your alarm systems off you
know like
>> I know that that was that was
>> real world impact is like the best
>> love real world impact I and I
>> that's my goal for the year
>> just you know text your victim right
text your victim be like your package is
here they click the link now their
alarm's off you know like the house and
rob the house that's exactly right a
real criminal could use that that like I
love the idea that a real criminal I
have stopped a real like maybe they
could have maybe they would have
>> stopped I mean, I actually think smart
lock I think smart lock or smart garage
door is even more impactful, though.
Like, if you can just open someone's
garage door up or unlock their door.
>> This could do that, too. This could do
all of that stuff. It could open
everything. I love that,
>> dude. I feel like JD is the kind of guy,
you know, he's So, context, he's a
doctor already, so he's making good
money, right? Yeah. But I feel like he's
the kind of guy that would do it and
then just rob the house just for like I
I exploited it.
>> I did. Well, I would do I wouldn't just
rob it. I would put stuff in the house.
>> I would put stuff inside the house.
>> Yeah, exactly. Get in the house. Still
get in there. Put a picture of this
report as a critical.
>> The report,
>> dude. We have to tell that story, JD.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> We can't tell the company, but we have
to tell that story. That should be the
next bug.
>> Oh my gosh. Okay. All right. Um JD, I
mean, you got a couple more bugs, man.
I'm I'm a sucker for a good bug story.
What What do you want to do next?
>> All right. I'll tell one more bug that
actually is Reszo and I's bug. If you
notice, I hack better when highle
hackers ask me that hack with them. I I
like try to bring my agame in that. So,
we were hacking on another site that um
is an e signature platform. Um, and
basically the way it works is that you
um the you make a uh you make a contract
and the contract you send it to the
person you want to sign it and they get
it in an email and then they click that
link and then they sign it.
>> Mh. and that and uh and we found that
the the person who creates the contract,
there's another API endpoint that really
wasn't that visible that you could get
to that would let the creator of the
contract see the link that was sent to
the recipient of the contract. So you
you could basically make a contract and
then sign it on behalf of the person who
you were sending it to and it just said
that they signed it. Like when you
clicked the sign thing, it was their
name that was that was signed. And so we
I mean to me that's the highest level
>> insane impact
>> that this this app can offer, right? But
when we submitted it to them,
>> they tried to close this thing like
three times on us, Justin. Like no,
they're still debating whether or not
they're going to accept it.
>> Yeah. So like they basically said that
it wasn't it wasn't the triager. It was
the actual like developers or like we
made it like this so that because we
didn't want the recipient to to anyway.
It doesn't matter what they were talking
about. It's a design principle thing is
it was design but you do run into these
issues from time to time where programs
are a little bit more resistant because
it's like okay well for the business use
case the use ease of access is like oh
we should be able to sign this
unauthenticated or whatever but at the
end of the day if you're leaking the URL
>> they should link the URL that's the bug
the bug is the leaking if they don't
want to do that anyway but so what I did
is I used this to create
>> a contract with the security team of
this
of the company saying that this is a
critical bug and will be paid as a
critical bug and that you and that you
agree that have them and I sent it in
the report.
>> Oh my gosh, dude.
>> Yeah, you you're contractually obligated
to get a critical.
>> Yeah. And I and I and I I was thinking
when they pulled back again of being
like, you signed the contract. It says
here you signed the contract. I don't
know what what we're debating about now.
>> Can you prove to me you didn't sign this
contract? Cuz if not,
>> you can't prove it's not. And the audit
trail says you signed this contract.
>> We we can go to court over this. Like
you agreed to it.
>> Yeah.
>> In the in the contract like it shows
what their email or like what
>> they're name.
>> They're emailing their name. There's
nothing that identifies the creator of
the contract as the signer of
>> do they need to have an account on that
website or is
>> that's why they say that's their
argument that they don't want the
recipient to have an account on the
website. They want anybody to be able to
sign it. But that's great. But then the
link should be
>> private.
>> Then the link then the link is the
security feature.
>> Yeah.
>> The security mechanism then is that you
got that link via email, right? And then
the only reason that it's not just
anybody is signing it is because you got
that link in your email, right? So if
you thus you have access to your email
and nobody else does, thus it must be
you signing it, right? So
>> that's it. That's little sense, man.
That makes little sense. It's a good
bug. I like it.
>> I said that in the contract. That was
part of the contract. That was funny.
Oh my gosh. Very good, man. Well, I feel
like uh I feel like we could kind of go
back and forth all day on um on stories,
but let's uh let's actually intro you.
Um so, uh guys, this is ExStor. He's
been running hackalongs for us for a
while now. So, most of you guys that are
like hardcore in the community know him.
Um but I will just say I'll brag on you
a little bit and then I'll let you do a
self intro as well. But I think XSS
doctor is like one of the people that
has kind of grown up in Bug Bounty in
this community in the CTVB community
that I am most proud of. Like if I think
of like oh you know what effects has the
CTVB community ha you know had on bug
bounty at at large and the fact that
excess doctor has you know grown up in
this environment is like one of my
proudest you know things. Um and yeah I
just have so much respect for you as a
hacker man. like the amount of passion
you bring. Very very rarely does the
amount of passion somebody brings to Bug
Bounty actually rival my own. But I I
feel I feel like uh you know we have
very very similar very compatible levels
of of passion for Bug Bounty and it's
very contagious
>> and passion for front end
>> and passion for front end right and uh
just
>> seeing the way you you tear apart
frameworks and apps and like and just
get right to the meat. um is just it's
very inspiring, man. So, you're
definitely a hacker I respect a ton and
I'm very glad to have you on.
>> Thank you. Well, I mean I'm I'm only for
real I only learned front end because of
you. Like I I'm not I'm not that's not a
joke. Like I I didn't even know about
it. Like I would listen to the podcast
and I'm like this guy seems it seems fun
what he's doing and then that's why I
learned all this stuff.
>> Dude, that's I'm so glad to hear that,
man. Um you're also also a doctor,
right? Your name is XSS doctor. Um, so
give us a little bit of background of
like how you landed on Puck Bounty as a
cardiologist and uh where you're at in
life now, I guess, like
>> Oh, yeah. So, so I basically I was uh I
started practice in 2019. I finished
fellowship and then like I was like all
about you know being a cardiologist and
then like co happened in 2020 2021 and
like co it was really crazy time in
medicine
>> uh for a lot of reasons but like for me
it was weird because like everyone was
dying of COVID and nobody was coming
into the hospital for heart disease
>> but I was still consulted for all the CO
patients because they had high cardiac
enzymes that's kind of beside the point
but anyway and so I was like both very
stressed and depressed about everybody
dying that I was seeing and kind of
bored uh because I wasn't doing any
cardiology and I had a very small child
that my that like when you have one kid
it's mostly your my wife now I have two
kids and it's like kind of half and half
but so I was like getting home early and
I was bored and depressed and kind of
like didn't you know and I'm like
scrolling on my phone and I see this
like learn to be a hacker in 12 hours go
from beginner the intermediate level is
what it said. I'm not going to say the
name. And this was like one of these
fake classes,
>> but I I'm like I want to that sounds
awesome. Like that's the coolest thing
I've ever heard.
>> Freaking algorithm showed you that. Like
that's what I want to know. Like I just
want to know what was in the algorithm
of like Instagram or whatever. That's
like okay JD is the most nerd snipable
human. Uh and what could we get him to
think that is cool that you know like
and they're like hacker. That's amazing.
>> He was on flipboard. Yeah. Oh.
>> Have you ever heard of Flipboard?
>> No.
>> That's like It's cuz I'm old. That's
like predates I still have it on my
phone. It's like when you flip and it
like will show you a different article
every time. And so I took the class. It
was obviously fraudulent.
>> But um but it was I was like obsessed. I
like didn't know about Cali. I've
downloaded Kali Linux and I'm and then
like I'm like all right I I I even
realized then this was BS. I I'm like I
go on Reddit R hacking and I'm like you
know how they had that like thing on the
top where they were like um how to be a
real hacker like and it's like don't be
a script kitty do CTFs. That's what that
posted thing said that CTF players if
you could be CTF player you could hack
anything is what that thing said.
>> So I spent the next like year and a half
>> doing CTFs uh mostly hack the box and
like obsessed with IPSC which I still am
by the way. I love IPSAC and um and
doing like if I'm like I don't even care
about hacking. If I could just do an
extreme box, I'm that's all I care about
in life, you know? Like I was just so
into it and like I spent that time I'm
like learning Python and like I'm like
I'm like trying to do these boxes and
I'm and then by the time I could do an
extreme box I'm like all right post said
I'm I'm a hacker.
>> I am a master hacker in fact you know
I'm an extreme hacker and so I'm like I
think like what kind of hacking am I
legally allowed to do? And I knew about
bug bounties. So I started to look at
bounty bug bounties and I'm like I don't
even know what I'm looking at right now.
Like I've never what is this? You know
like I it's I don't know how many people
have had that experience like where
you're doing CTFs and you hack the box
and try hackme. When you look at the
Kaido output or the burp output of a
real website, it looks drastically
different than that.
>> Totally.
>> And the types of bugs you look for are
drastically different. Like I thought
everything was going to be like PHP to
rce. Yeah,
>> you know, VHV LFI to RC. To me, that was
I was gonna find that every day.
>> Um, great.
>> And then I took Jason's Hadex's bug
bounty methodology course and I found my
first couple bugs during that. Um, and I
started hacking sort of in that method
for a while. Mhm.
>> But it with that um type of widescope
hacking, you need a competitive I find
that you need a competitive advantage
like extremely good automation or like
some something that makes you better
than the people with the automation,
>> which I did not have.
>> And then I started listening to podcast
and that's kind of where I and I I
realized I'm like why aren't I finding
that many bugs? And and then you were
finding a lot of bugs. So I'm like,
let's let's see what the hacking like
this guy would be like.
>> Yeah.
>> And and that's kind of how I got into
client side.
>> Dude, that's that's amazing, man. Yeah,
that is a that is such a amazing journey
and I'm so glad that I was a part of
that. Uh that just gives me goosebumps.
That's why we do the pod. Um I I I do
want to jump back to I guess a function
of your rhetoric that it keeps coming
out which is and this was the most
important thing in my life you know and
like you're like this was and then I
felt like you know that I if I could
just solve an extreme box then it would
just be like the whole purpose of my
existence you know like and I I often
find you know myself talking like that
as well is like if I could just like pop
this this bug this would like make my
life you know um
>> I can't sleep well. I think I think that
is if I had to to if I had to guess I
think that is probably one of the
reasons why you have the success that
you that you've had is that like super
strong passion allin like this is what
is this is the thing I am very decided
and focused that this is the thing that
is the most important to me right now
you know
>> yeah it's very goal oriented too and I
think that and it's also kind of hopeful
like u it's optimistic I think the mix
of passion optimism and goal oriented
thinking is like a really really um
strong mix for success and a lot of top
hackers.
>> That's a really good way to put it. I
agree with that. And I see a lot of
hackers like veering towards negativity
and I think that hurts them a lot when
they don't find bugs or when they when
they get some bad situation with triage.
Bug bounty is terrible. I hate bug
bounty. And then it's like hard to hack
like that.
>> Yeah.
>> JD man. Anytime I message him an idea,
JD is always like, "Yes, let's do it.
Yes, let's do it." Even even if he's
literally more hacking, are you crazy?
Do more hacking all day.
>> Oh my gosh, I love you guys. Uh I think
that that is definitely a part of the
secret sauce, but I also think it puts
us all in a very unique position for
burnout. Um and it's possible that your
passion is just, you know, bottomless
and endless. But I also heard a little
bit of like if I don't pop this bug, I'm
gonna quit bug bounty forever and this
is the end of my life and I I hate my
life, you know. So there there are a lot
of ups and downs with this, right? So I
in more so than I I would ask the normal
um you know guest on critical thinking,
I want to ask you how do you deal with
the ups and downs of this being such an
extreme person and is burnout a part of
your your flow? Yeah, I'm not gonna I'm
I'm I'm actually not the right person to
ask about this because I'm completely
different than everybody. I not
everybody a lot of people at least
because I I don't like this is solely
for fun.
>> Mh.
>> And so when I don't like doing one
aspect of hacking, I will switch
completely at a whim to a different
completely different like I'll like like
I stopped hacking once for four months
to learn go. You know what I mean? like
>> like I just I don't care about doing
that. And if I'm into doing that, like I
I was I did a lot of I did coding for a
while. I I helped with that fat with
fabric. Uh and that's I did that like
for months. I didn't hack basically cuz
I was just really into that. And I think
that that that stops me from burning
out. Um like just following like a like
a passion and being able financially to
do that is very helpful. And I think
it's made me a better hacker in the end,
but it's made me make less money in the
end. because um like I don't go 5 days
straight on a target in order to find a
50 bugs.
>> Yeah.
>> Which would make me more money. Um I I
don't think I can do that. Uh like in my
life, I don't have enough time to do
that,
>> right?
>> Um uh but anyway, that's that's my
answer. I'm not going to burn out
because of that.
>> I've asked you before though, like if
you have such passion for it, would you
go full-time Bug Bounty? What is hard? I
spent a lot of time being a doctor. Like
I spent a lot of time trying to be a
doctor. Like it it my like it I I
finished training when I was like
>> 2019. I was like 36. Like I I basically
like I it was like decades of my life
and it's hard and it's fun being a
doctor. I love being a doctor and I have
like all these patients that need me. I
don't think I cannot I don't think I can
stop doing that. I will say Justin, this
thought has crossed my mind a lot too
because uh for listeners that don't
know, basically my entire hackbot
system, me and JD are just kind of 50/50
on and there's a lot of reasons for
that. Like I think there's a lot of
really cool things like, you know, he's
able to triage like frontend stuff that
I'm that I would struggle to triage and
lots of other things I actually think
that people should probably partner half
and half on on um hackbot creation um
because you get twice as much velocity.
And anyways, I'll I'll table that for
now. Um, the one thing that I have
thought a lot about Justin is like if if
he and I do, you know, a million in
bounties this year just like completely
crazy. It goes really well, could I talk
him into it? And I think that the best I
could do about a million dollars, you
know, we never mentioned a million
dollars here.
>> Uh, and I think the best I could do is
talk him down to like part-time work,
you know?
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know. It's It depends on a lot
of things. It's it's it's hard to
There's no such thing as parttime. It's
a cardiologist. It does. I know
part-time cardiologists and it they they
still work full-time. It's hard to be a
part-time cardiologist.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I imagine so. And it's and
it's something I think there's also a
weight to that as a as a physician like
you
and this is something we've talked I
think when we went out to dinner that
one time it's like well you know if
you're so passionate about bug bounty
but you're also a cardiologist like you
you've got to really be disciplined in
that
>> you need to be paying you know
sufficient attention to your profession
because it's not something that is like
you can just skate by on as if you were
like a government employee you know
doing some IT job
>> there's a lot of pressure there's a lot
of pressure for your patient And you can
make one mistake and like their life is
over. Obviously, your life is is also
harmed a great deal by that one mistake.
But
>> yeah, so that's intense, man. I think
that you're living a very intense um you
know, environment there, but but I think
you've also mentioned like your work
hours are pretty good and that you can
still find time to hack and stuff like
that and you can reschedule patients and
>> efficient. It's my efficiency. It's
which anyway,
>> I can do a whole podcast on efficiency.
>> Yeah. Well, I actually should do that. I
think it's like a superpower. Yeah.
>> I I know we said we were going to focus
on the research, but contarch. So, one
last question though. You context switch
a lot, right? Which I think is something
that is a lot of hackers struggle with,
particularly me. I need focused.
>> I mean, actually, you know, sort of the
n the the environment around you, you
know, forces you to evolve. So, now that
I have kids, I am getting a little bit
better at like, you know, dealing with
distraction then coming back. But you do
it in a way that I've never seen, which
is I've got a patient now. I've got six
minutes to hack and I hack and then I go
back, you know, like
>> Yeah. Well, that's that's not uh that's
not a super that's in my disease. Like I
have ADD uh that used to be medicated
when I was in high school and then I did
I stopped medicating my ADD and I just
figured out how to live my life in such
a way that works with my brain. And that
includes if I'm doing something that I'm
not having fun doing, I can do it in
short spurts and then switch to another
not fun activity and then switch back
and I'm able to do that. But if I'm
obviously if I'm into a thing like if
I'm in the middle of a bug chain, I
could do that for like a week without
sleeping. But if I'm doing like recon on
a target, which I'm I'm not a huge fan
of that, then I have to context switch
frequently in order to complete the
task. But that is a my brain thing and
not like what I suggest for others
around me. But it helps me in context
switching like medicine and hacking and
my kids um and stuff. But that's
>> Wow. Very interesting, dude. I don't I
don't know how that works for you, but
uh more power to you cuz it's clearly
getting results.
>> You have the opposite. You have
something that nobody else has, which is
you are have like the the hyperfocus of
ADD without having ADD and you just have
it all the time. Like that's like that's
like that's an actual superpower. Like
we we we have I have a problem and you
have actual superower.
>> I I wish I could get on something like
Riddle and so I could do what Justin
does, but I literally
>> It's unreal.
>> It's unreal. It is It is a little bit
odd too, man. I I do think um just as
like a you don't know, self-proclaimed
neurotypical here. uh like it I do I do
really value the fact that I can just
sit down and and focus for a very long
time and like you know stay locked in
and stuff like that but I mean you
really do feel it when your body is off
too like if you get a bad I've got this
whoop right if you get a bad you know
night sleep or you know you're just not
your body is not at at you know good
performance levels or whatever like and
I'm sitting here I'm trying to focus I'm
like man why can I not like focus on
this you know so it is crazy when as you
become more aware of you you learn how
to like optimize your your life around
that if you're really trying to focus
hard. Um
>> I have to feel physically good in order
to hack well. I agree. If even if I have
one drink the night before, I'm older
than you guys. So I like one drink is a
lot is a lot for me. I mean even though
I do it, but but I'm a worse hacker the
next day. Even with one drink, I'm a
worse hacker.
>> I I stopped being able to pro process
alcohol at like 25. Like I at 25 like I
started, you know, if I had a glass of
wine, I would feel it like the next day
actively. And I'm like, "All right,
well, guess I'm done with that." So, I I
don't drink anymore. Um, but yeah, I So,
all that aside, let's get to the
technical meat. Well, Richard, go ahead
and put in a cut here as well, you know,
for like if people want to like jump to
this point uh in the podcast. Um, let's
get to the research. Okay. So, you I
messaged you about this episode and I
was like, "Hey, man, you know, maybe we
could do something with like client side
paths or like client side path
traversal." And then you're like, "Sure
thing." And then like I come over and
there's like this book on client side
path traversals. There's an app on
client side path parsing. There's like
the nuances of every single framework
outlined. I swear, dude, that and I read
through it all and it's like beautifully
written. Uh
>> well, did you ever see The Price is
Right? You ever see the show The Price
is Right? I have.
>> You know when they call the person down
>> and and that person's all excited to be
on the Price is Right because they've
been watching it for years. I am
currently right now on the Price is
Right and you have called me down. Like
are you going to are you is this going
to be a bad episode?
>> No, this is not going to be a bad
episode. This better be a fantastic
episode.
>> This is so funny cuz we just view you as
our friend and you literally lead
hackalongs. Like you've popped bugs
during Justin's stream. Like you're not
you're not
>> listen to you guys every Thursday.
That's my routine for years.
>> For years.
>> Oh man, that's amazing, dude. Frick. I
love this. I love this community. Okay.
Um so we now have a very long research
paper uh that will be going on the
research lab. So uh you can find that at
lab.ctb.show
and uh that outlines client side path
traversals across every single major
framework by our boy XSS doctor.
>> Yeah, you should you should take one
minute to tell us uh how you wrote that
because Justin loved it.
>> Okay. Yeah, dude. Okay. So yeah, let me
set the scene for that. Great great lead
in Reszo. Um, as I read through this, I
was like, "Oh man, like JD sat down here
and like wrote this like by hand, every
single line." And you know, that's so
rare nowadays with AI. Is that actually
what happened? Cuz it
>> I literally the the answer is this what
you're reading was written by me, but
the the process by which was written by
me is is slightly different. So like
basically
this is let me talk about the research
first, then we can talk about how I I
did it. Basically, um I started out by I
I uh I love client side path traversal.
It's my favorite bug u class and I love
playing with client side path. The first
thing I look at ever on a on a target is
is all the client side paths.
>> Same.
>> And I when I'm looking for client side
path traversal, I basically I don't even
look at the code in the beginning. I
just like find a path that looks like
it's custom like slash settingss doctor
and then I'll start putting encodings at
the end of that percent 2F percent 252F
percent 5C sometimes unic code although
for some reason now I understand why but
it never it doesn't work unic code uh
often and so and then I'll I'll look for
an API call on the back end I'll often
also use bus factors fantastic uh gecko
extension which I do all the time which
basically is just looking for reflection
in the API call.
>> Mh.
>> And then um if I find that and I find
traversal on the back end, I'll then
look to see if um if if there's any
impact of that, whether it's a curf or
XSS. Um, but when Justin asked me to do
this client side path episode, I thought
it would be cool to like look through
every framework and to find out why it
was sometimes working. Why percent 2F
sometimes work percent 5C? Like is it
just like the developer doing something
weird or is there something that is
unique to the frameworks? So I looked at
uh nine I actually looked at 10
frameworks in the beginning but I I
thought it was too long so I ended up
just doing it on eight. And so that's uh
React uh Next, Ember, Vue, Angular,
something called Solid State. Um am I
missing one?
>> Nux. I did NXT also. Um I think that's
it. And so um install kit. Install kit.
>> Yeah.
>> And so the way that I did it was that I
had
AI build me labs.
That's the first thing I did is I say
build me a lab for React. I want it to
have um this. So basically like take a
path parameter and and uh put it into an
API call. Take a query parameter, put it
into API call. How is it doing that? And
then I would I would look at it, play
with it, and then ask AI.
>> Um yeah,
>> ask AI how it really that's a really
good flow. Sorry, I know I was I was
gesturing with my hands here for those
that are on audio, but um yeah, that's a
really good way of doing it, too,
because the AI of course is going to
produce the code that is most common
>> that it was trained off of, right? So,
if you're looking to like replicate
common code patterns
>> used by developers in the specific
language, then that's like AI is [__]
right? you know, like that's that's so
you had to generate all the labs and
then you worked back from there or
>> so I I would do the labs and I' I'd find
the places that
>> it worked
>> on and then I would ask AI to point me
to the code in the developer code like
in the react code for example to like
where is this parsed how is this parsed
like like when um so like thinking about
let's say that client side path example
for um so like you're a developer and
you want to make a
you want to make a path to um the
slashabout. Like that's easy, right?
Like you just like basically say
slashabout. This is the JavaScript you
want to be on that page. This is what
you want the page to look like. But
let's say you want slash settingss
doctor.
That XSS doctor is going to be custom
for every user. And so that is going to
be defined a certain way in every
different framework. Mhm.
>> Um and so like in React for example um
it would be like SL settings
user ID and so then I thought the
developer needs to get that somehow and
then use that in a way that however they
want to use it they have to get that
information because if I was a developer
and I wanted to make let's say slash
settingss
doctor and then I would make an API call
to slap APIXS doctor or API v1 XSS
doctor.
Uh they would what they would do is
they'd get that value as a variable and
then pass it into the API call which is
actually how it works you know and in
React that would be on the front end
sometimes it's on the back end. We could
talk about that and so um I had AI point
me towards the exact code and I would
keep asking it questions. I be like
what's it doing here? Like like why is
it doing this? Like what is this? What
is this? Um, and then I would look at it
with AI to find out. So that's how I did
the research
>> to trace it through the various
components in
>> yes
>> React's internal repository or whatever
framework.
>> Correct. And then I would I would say
why is it you are all coding here? Like
what's happening here? Like what what's
the function? Show me that function.
>> So I would I would do that. Um and then
I had all the research done for all the
things and then I'm like write the blog
article for me. Just write it. you know,
there here are some blogs I've written
before. Put make it sound like that.
Yeah,
>> that's literally what I did. And I wrote
it and I'm like, this is pretty good.
So, I sent it out to like Reszo and and
Demo and you although you didn't read
it, thank god. Um, and that you and you
wouldn't have liked it and Buzz Factor
and everyone's like, "This is okay, but
like I could just get AI to write me a
blog." Like, why did you get AI to write
me a blog?
>> So then,
>> True, true. I rewrote it all myself.
>> Yeah, I think I think it feels okay. So
So then what you did is you looked at
the blog post and then you like hand
rewrote it. Is that is that right?
>> Yeah, I hand rewrote everything. I No, I
just started at the beginning. I didn't
like hand rewrite line by line. Like I I
just wrote my own blog article.
>> Okay.
>> Using the research.
>> Gotcha. Gotcha. Gotcha. Yeah. Because
>> I there are certain lines I left in from
the AI. Yeah.
>> And some of them maybe you could tell
they're in there. uh but
>> I couldn't personally but
>> there were many there I I left but
mostly it was me uh in this particular
one uh cuz I once uh uh submitted a bug
with you
>> and I had AI write the report and you
were quite unhappy with that report um
and I felt bad
>> wasn't good bro
>> it was not good I know I felt really bad
when you when you when you so I'm like I
can't submit a blog article for
>> in your defense it actually did get
triaged
>> got paid got paid two days later
>> it did I I like I said I I messaged you
and I was like look JD this is [__] like
and and this doesn't have like a a very
actionable P like where is the click and
see impact right like like I really
think that that's essential like you you
and you did have a you know there was a
ton of stuff there's a lot of detailed
information it was like you know it
outlined everything but as a as a you
know as a I don't know as a person
reading the report I wanted to see go to
this link click and then note what
happens on their site, you know, that
sort of thing. And I didn't see it, but
somehow
>> No, you're right. It was a terrible
article. It was a terrible It was a
terrible No, you were right. And I felt
bad, not because of you, but because I
I'm like I That was not the best work I
could have done there. But it's so It's
so seductive to have AI write the report
for you.
>> It is
>> because it's so boring sometimes to
write the report. Sometimes it depends
on the bug. If if I love the bug, if if
a bug is part of my heart, I like
writing it. But if the bug is not part
of my heart and it's just like I like I
don't like writing it.
>> The bug is part of my heart. Dude,
>> let me give like a like just like two
really quick tips for writing better
reports. You know, 90% of people
listening probably already do this, but
if you don't, definitely tell it to be
concise and just technical and leave out
any kind of fluff. But the other thing
that I found that is really really um
good for having it write good reports
Justin especially for what you're
talking about is I've told it to always
use attacker victim language and be
extremely clear about when the victim
does or like sorry given these
preconditions because like often the AI
whenever it starts to wrap that would be
like wait the precondition is that
you're already a super admin oh man this
actually isn't a bug right so like you
know make make sure it gives the
preconditions for what the victim is and
what the attacker is and then make sure
that it frames it in attacker victim
language. So, you know, an attacker
would set up this and then a victim
would do this and then this outcome will
occur and that massively improves the
reports.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'm
>> It's I don't know. It depends on the
it's it's very hard for me because
sometimes I just want it I I found the
bug, I just want it submitted.
>> Yeah. I think at the end of the day like
you should definitely write concise,
technical, you know, to the point
reports, right? I think, and this is
actually something I said on the goals
goals episode at the beginning of this
year, you know, I want to do better
detail, you know, in my reports, but I
think if you're gonna skimp somewhere,
skimp on the report and don't skip on
the PC. Like if your PC speaks for
itself,
>> there is a high chance that the company
will like take that report seriously,
right? If you're if if you're, you know,
>> and when Justin says P, he doesn't just
mean like the actual script. He means
like the video showing exactly what
happens. Yeah, the video, the the actual
script itself, you know, all of that,
you know, they will fill in the blanks
on the report, right? Uh or they will
ask you to fill in the blanks on the
report. If you write a report with no PC
and no, you know, video, then it's it's
hard for them to go from zero context
to, oh, I read through this thing and I
know, you know, how it works and I can
actually implement it myself, you know,
given none of your pre-nowledge, right?
So, um I don't know. I think that that's
I think if you're gonna skimp on on one
area, definitely don't make it the the
PC. Um
>> I'm gonna try to do them all myself.
Anyway,
>> I think that's good. I think that's
good. All right, let's get to the
research. So um I mean just having read
through it essentially what this
research shows and you can correct me
where where I'm wrong in any way is an
analysis of these these frameworks how
um path parameters quer parameters hash
parameters are parsed across the
frameworks and even some serverside
rendering stuff which was very
interesting to me. Um and then uh how
these CSPTs actually which is client
side path traversal get um in they how
they occur within these frameworks. What
what parsing of the of the parameters? a
parsing of the routes should we be
looking for and understanding okay you
know in this scenario our percent 2F is
going to turn into a slash and we've
even got percent 252F now that we can
you know utilize in this specific
environment uh versus like um
understanding where you know what single
page application frameworks are not
going to do that um and you're wasting
your time looking for for uh CSPTs is
that is that accurate
>> yeah I mean basically like when we're in
this situation,
the source is going to be something in
the URL bar and the sync in this just in
this for this gadget is going to be the
fetch or the the API call.
>> Mhm.
>> So if you think about that like what is
the process by which the the thing that
the thing in the URL bar gets to the API
call to in order to exploit it there's
another sync right? there's going to be
either the the the CSURF sync or the XSS
sync or however else you want to exploit
this or the or the SSRF or secondary
path traversal sync um on the server.
But um so if you you know in the URL bar
the um Oh, good. Nice. Yeah, I've got
the
>> the three places that you that you may
um that you may your your three sources
there are either the path itself, the
query parameter or the hash parameter.
Um the query parameter, everyone is
always testing this from the query
parameter, but I like to start from the
path. To be honest, my most impactful um
CSPTs have been from the path. Same,
>> not from the Yeah,
>> I agree. I think I think it actually
very often happens in in in the path
parameter
>> more almost more often because they're I
feel like the developers are looking for
it from the query parameter
>> more or something.
>> I also feel like they often take query
parameters and put them in query
parameters versus like path values get
put in path values. Yes.
>> Does that make sense? Yeah.
>> Yes. That's Yeah. And and interestingly
in my research the path was the most
interesting
>> um I found the most interesting things
basically there. So um you can even go
down go down to like the all the way on
the bottom to that to that. Um so so
like basically for people who are like
not client side people it's like again
it's like the way you have to think
about it is that there is each the a
front-end JavaScript framework I guess
just to introduce that is there the p
the path parameter in the URL bar is not
mapping to a folder on the server or a
file on the server like it would be for
like PHP or like a multi- um a
multi-page framework, an old one of
these older framework IIS. Um, instead
these uh JavaScript frameworks they the
URL bar they they take what's on the URL
bar and uh the path in the URL and and
that will be sent to the code and the
code will use that to determine what
shows up on the page, what code paths
are gone down, what lazy loaded
JavaScript files are loaded, um what API
calls are sent out from from that place.
And so um when you have a dynamic
path parameter, a path parameter that's
not like just slashabout but like
slashabout xss doctor slashfiles
slashmd5 sum, you know, um the way that
they reference those
that as the developer there's a function
that they call either on the front or
the back end that gets that value back
for the developer and then the developer
can do something with that.
>> Okay. And so let me let me let me pause
and and try to summarize and make sure
I'm tracking with you. Okay. So unlike
you know PHP or IAS, right? Those are
sort of file system based HTTP servers,
right? Um we've got those and then we've
got like APIs, right? Modern modern
paths where um a program is actually
handling the the parsing of these
routes, right? So those are two types of
paths that we're familiar with. Then
there's also like a third one which is
like a client side router right which is
a a router that is occurring within your
own browser for single page
applications. So um the JavaScript code
on the client side is parsing the the
the path from the URL and then routing
you to some specific you know view or or
some page within the single page
application. Uh and that's what we're
talking about is dealing with the
parameters of those paths. So um the you
know like you mentioned SLabout XSS
doctor whatever XSS doctor might be a
dynamic value there could be
SLabouterator
right and what we're what we're looking
into here is how these client side
routing engines parse that dynamic
component is that am I am I tracking
with you
>> that's exactly right that's what I
wanted to look at that was like the the
and you know uh for this part of the
research yeah and so um and then another
question I had was that which functions
in which frameworks decode by default.
>> So if you put in /xs doctors slash
percent 2f or percent 252f or percent 5c
which I actually have to put back put in
there um which ones are URL decoded by
default because that would if it was URL
decoded by default that would make the
developer less likely we're more more
likely to have a misconfiguration
putting that directly into the API call.
Um, and I found that they all all the
frameworks have at least
>> almost all the frameworks have a way to
to have a um a vulnerable way to
>> a vulnerable primitive, a vulnerable
function that will take the path
parameter and auto decode it as if it
was a query parameter.
>> Yeah. And sometimes double URL decode
it.
>> That's that's crazy, man. The double URL
I'm looking at the table here. There is
on React there's a double URL decode.
>> The worst thing about React is that
there was actually a issue a GitHub
issue
um saying that there was a double URL uh
decoding bug. They fixed it but then
reintroduced it later in a different
manner. Uh so it's there's still anyway
uh React it's called the use params
which is important if you're going to
take anything away from from this
research you should look at this because
this is a great way to to find in the
code what's going on. Um like you know
if you if uh in in use uh in React uh
basically the developer would say let
squiggly squiggly bracket user ID equals
use params and that would bring back
that user ID um into the code and then
if it's passing that directly into a
fetch that's a CSPT or it could be doing
other stuff with it. It could be putting
that directly into an a dangerous set in
our HTML. You never know. Um but that's
a good way thing to look at and it will
double URL decode that
>> um view
>> everything is is uh everything is
vulnerable to this angular uh it's
pretty vulnerable. Um
uh next
is mostly not vulnerable except uh next
has this thing called uh also has a use
params function which is does not auto
decode uh the parameter but on the
server side
it uses something called await params
which is the async version of of use
params that is often is almost always
used on the server side and that is auto
decoded.
>> And if you think about what that means
is that if on a next app if you're using
uh server side routing um and you are
using a backend API in as opposed to a
front-end API because in next you can
kind of choose what you do. it can kind
of be more front end or more backend and
that's kind of why a lot of people use
next but why else use next if you're not
going to use some amount of backend
>> right
>> fanciness and so if you await params
uh and then pass that directly to the
backend API that will lead to secondary
context path reversal
>> okay so I'm gonna that's the one we're
going to double click into for a second
okay
>> that's in the in the syncs section of Is
it? Okay. So, let me see if I can find
it here.
>> All right. So, we found it. Um, I'm
looking at this. So, this is a very
interesting case. So, what you're saying
here is that as an as an attacker on the
client side, we can send a send a
request, we can make the victim's
browser send a request. Mhm.
>> That request uh will not trigger a a
client side path traversal because the
use params on the client side in next
will keep the uh percent 2f encoded
rather than um decoding it to a slash
incur incurring a traversal. when that
actually gets passed to the server side
in some capacity there if a weight
params is used it will it will actually
resolve those percent 2FS2
uh slashes and incur some sort of server
side path traversal with the victim's
credentials that were sent from the
browser
>> correct and the the reason behind this
is that uh next has two routing systems
Next is weird, right? Because next is is
supposed to be like the developer
supposed to kind of choose how much
front end and back end they want.
There's a front end only uh next, which
I didn't really look at that much. But
in this situation that I'm describing,
which is basically a hybrid model, the
the path is sent always starts at the
server. There's no front-end use params
in this situation. The the URL bar is
sent to the server which parses it um in
however way they want to do it. If they
use await params, that's what it's
called, the await function, await
params, that's URL decoded by default.
And then if you're doing that and you
pass that to slap API slash, you know,
internal API.com
uh slash this param, you'll get
secondary context patch reversal.
>> Okay, so this doesn't rely on any client
side code at all.
it in this particular circumstance of of
next uh there's no client side code in
this situation. It's going straight to
the server. The server's parsing it and
passing it to the backend API.
>> Okay.
>> Um there are front end imple
implementations but those mostly use um
uh the the the nonvulnerable code path.
>> Yeah. It's a little interesting though
because like so so essentially what this
is is a um secondary context path
reversal.
>> Yes. Is that is that what you're
describing here?
>> That's correct. That would be
>> Yeah. I wonder if there's another layer
though. I wonder if there's a
client side induced
uh you know secondary context path
reversal that that is happening here
where it doesn't you know de
I don't I don't even know how this maybe
maybe I'm thinking about this wrong but
like if there is a client side route
that takes a path parameter puts that
into an API request that is not so we're
not incurring the path traversal at this
point right puts it into that API
request with off you know cookies which
is not something we could have triggered
from C cross-sight context puts it into
that you know subresource request it is
not incurring a path reversal at this
point because it's not decoded then that
is sent to the server the server uses
await params then it is decoded
>> and then that's not how that's not how
that's not how next works yeah the in
this situation uh you have to think of
next a little different than react the
um there there could be as you're
describing like a fetch request on the
front end to an API
But that is usually a different
>> thing than the back end of next.
>> I see. I see what you're saying. Cuz you
see what I'm saying? It's almost like a
It's like a server side single page.
>> Yeah,
>> next is weird. I I guess some people
want server side functions, but but
spelt is the same way where spelt has
has a backend and a front end and then
maybe external APIs and spelt is also
vulnerable to the secondary context path
reversal. And I did the the a second
answer to your question is I didn't look
at the front-end only implementation of
Nex.js. I only looked at this what I
consider to be like the normal
implementation of Nex.js which is that
the path is sent to the server and the
server does the stuff.
>> Okay.
>> Um but uh I'm not a Nex developer so uh
maybe uh there's other implementations
that are have different um have
different things. Um so that's that's
one uh anyway. Sorry.
>> Yeah. No, that that makes sense. I think
that that's uh that's a valuable route
and it it's helpful I mean even if for
no other thing than just to feed this to
AI as well and just be like hey point
out to me the various spots in a
codebase in a next codebase where
they're using await prams versus you
know whatever other way you're supposed
to process it.
>> I'm not going to test for CSP on next
using the path anymore. I can I may tech
for secondary context but like there's
no reason like next will not be
vulnerable to that.
>> Interesting. um in based on this
research uh and neither will um solid
solid which I had actually hadn't heard
that much of before this
>> solid start
>> solid start yeah because there's no
vulnerable code pass in those situations
um for various reasons
>> very
>> that's that's uh but I will test for it
like crazy and view is very vulnerable
um
>> react is the most right you know
>> view is even more
But React's very You're right. You know,
the double URL encoding thing is uh is
is it makes it the most vulnerable.
Yeah.
>> Um I hope they don't I mean I guess I
hope they do patch it. I hope
everything's secure, but
>> Well, we were kind of talking about this
a little bit beforehand like it's it's
impossible to like curve you can patch,
right? Because there's some something
you know they did a really good job
patching it with same site cookies,
right? you and Caesar still exists, but
I mean for anybody who experienced the
prevalence of CSUF prior to same site
cookies like or same site lacks default
cookies, it was way more um
>> around back then
>> and and uh but this one you literally
can't fix because there's no way that
they can fix it at the sync level,
right? Because uh you're doing string
oftent times you're doing string
concatenation prior to passing it to
fetch or whatever, right? So all it sees
is is a concatenated string, right? You
know, one string that's al together and
you can't fix that at the source level
or else you retroactively break a bunch
of stuff.
>> Um, so I really think I think it's
impossible.
>> It has to be on the developer level.
That's the problem. And that's why it's
always going to be around because the
developer is going to need the URL
decoded value at some point.
>> Yeah,
>> that's that like they need to URL decode
it. If they don't do like it's going to
break things if you don't do that. So
then you have to always re-encode it
when you're passing it to a a backend to
that's the answer but but it's not going
to be fixed on the framework level.
>> I suppos
I got a good question.
>> If you all were on an app and you you
can pick a framework if you want and you
could only register one username because
I mean obviously we could just create a
bunch of accounts or whatever but you
could register one username that would
just break CSPT if they're not blocking
the right characters. What's that single
username you would pick?
Like would it be just like
>> doctor percent 2f dot dot 2% 2e percent
2F booya kasha it's got to be buasha in
the end dude
>> so you would actually you would put it
in all three characters encoded
>> I I to be honest I never I don't do it
like that I don't that's not how I test
I don't like I don't create I would
always test it low the nice thing about
client side is you could you don't have
to actually save the malicious username
in order to see if it's vulnerable you
could always set a match and replace or
just do something like that because it's
client side.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I do think that certainly
if you could smuggle uh those characters
in the um you know percent 2F the slash
the backslash the um question mark the
hashtag all of those sort of have
meaning from a from that perspective.
Um, I also think just going back to what
you were saying before though about
fixing it JD, I think one of the things
that could be interesting is providing
developers with a almost like prepared
queries primitive inside of your your
framework language. So if you're doing a
fetch, you provide like a base URL and
that base URL has I mean you can't use a
question mark or whatever because
question mark is you know query
parameter start but like you you've got
like a maybe like a tilda or something
like that that will get substituted with
your prepared query you know values that
you provide in either in an array
afterwards or in like a sequence of
parameters to that function and then it
will handle the string interpolation
itself because the value that you're
providing is always supposed to be you
are you know
>> just the value not not some path piece
right does that would that solve it you
think
>> no that that's the answer but I I will
come back and say that that is
definitely the answer that's the right
answer but like what did it take for SQL
injection to be this rare it took like
an entire
>> the entire developer community
>> getting together and and prioritizing
this because it was such an impactful
bug and I would argue that the
developers do not consider this as
impactful of a bug
>> and it's it would be like think of how
often they use dangerously set in HTML
when they shouldn't
>> you know they I mean I see it on every
app I see every every React app they're
using it like crazy they're passing user
control and stuff in there passing API
in there
>> because they don't care as much I mean
you know maybe they do but it feels to
me like SQL injection is something they
took much more seriously
>> certainly and I and I think also another
piece of that was that the whole
ecosystem turned over since SQL existed
it, right? SQL was one of SQL injection
was one of the first, you know,
vulnerabilities that really got
prevalence and then since then every
single framework has been rewritten and,
you know, has, you know, shifted to a
different framework or or evolved in a
serious way. So, it makes it easy for
them to like have those primitives
change, right? But I do think like if a
good step in the right direction against
CSPT would would maybe be the Chrome
team pushing a fetch um a fetch version
or a fetch uh alternative that has the
string interpolation.
>> Safe fetch.
>> Yeah, safe fetch or
>> Yeah, that's a really good idea.
>> But see, you can't rename I was going to
say like or renaming fetch bad fetch,
you know,
>> bad fetch. Yeah, you can't do it.
>> Fetch is very vulnerable. Yeah,
>> fetch is the most vulnerable thing in I
mean that's not true. Everything in
JavaScript is vulnerable, but fetch is
not a safe function. It as you have said
it takes out tabs.
>> Yeah.
>> Um that that which is the best W bypass
I've ever It's honest. I I don't know.
I'll say it percent 2F percent 09
percent 5C
is sorry dot dot dot sorry percent 2F
percent 2e percent 09% 2e percent 5C is
the best W bypass I've ever used in my
entire life. I love it. I use it all the
time and it works 100% of the time. I
haven't seen a W Oh,
>> I don't know. I don't know if we're
going to let that I don't know if we're
going to let that run. Uh, Richard, we
might bleep that. I don't know. That's
>> It's so good. But if we can't I mean,
I'm sorry to say if you can't bleep it
on this podcast.
>> You're true. You're true.
>> That's the point of this podcast.
>> Yeah. So, anyway, that is a very
powerful W bypass. Ryan, I know you're
listening to this. Don't you
>> turn Ryan, turn it off, man. Turn it
off. I was just thinking about Ryan. I
was thinking about him
>> freaking
providers listening to this podcast. Um,
but yeah, totally. I I agree. Yeah, I
think that that is very strong. Um and
and fetch certainly is vulnerable. Um I
will say there is one more vulnerable
though, which is the freaking um which
one is it? I think it's Axios. Some
versions Axio really AI
>> that will like auto run the JS code in a
JSON p callback
>> if you know that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. There's like there's one of
them. I I got to go look it up. Maybe
I'll put it in the show notes, but
there's I believe some versions of Axios
or maybe it's one of the jQuery um ones.
If you know if you pass traversal, if
you client side pass traversal it to a
JSON P endpoint, it will just run the
JavaScript call back.
>> Oh my god. You know, I think Axios is a
wrapper around fetch. Like I think Axio
uses fetch, right? Like it's like I
haven't looked at the Axios code, but I
guarantee you
>> demo has looked at that code and I'm
going to ask him right after this. He
knows exactly why it's doing that.
>> I think it's probably XHR um request uh
because Axios is a little older and I
think fetch is like a uh a newer I say
newer now I'm getting I'm aging myself a
little bit here but like uh you know
newer primitive. Um okay awesome. Yeah.
So that we did go down a little bit of a
rabbit rabbit trail there, but fixing
CSPT, you know, it would be cool if the
browsers put in some string
interpolation included um fetch function
call uh to try to get those resolved and
then have the frameworks try to adopt
that at a framework level. Um
>> that that's a good fix.
>> Uh so let's continue to go through some
of the research here uh on the path
stuff. I mean we can just look at this
maybe it's easier for everybody in the
audio medium to just you know talk
through this table essentially but we've
got react router that decodes react
routers use params decodes percent tof
to slash and percent 2e uh percent 2e to
dot dot
>> everything
>> and double URL codes as well
>> yeah and double URL
>> um the only other place we see double
URL encoding there's no other place we
see double URL encoding without
developer sourced code in any of the
other top frameworks. Is that accurate?
>> In the path. That's correct.
>> In the path. Yes. Um
>> in the path.
>> Where it gets really hit or miss is do
they double decode percent 2e across
various frameworks. Um most of the time
we see yes, but there are some nos at at
solid start and nux server level.
They'll just leave it straight as is.
Right.
>> Okay.
>> That's right. And then um another thing
is I need to include
>> backslash in this. I I I didn't do it
>> partly because this is the like the
longest article I've ever written
including in medicine.
>> This is very long.
>> Um it's very long. I and I could I also
like kind of didn't do as much on the
hash because it's so I think it's like
15 pages. It's like some amazing amount
of
>> Yeah.
>> Uh so I
>> break down the code paths for each
individual framework. It's very helpful.
>> That's kind of what I I wanted to do.
And also, um, I'm also going to include
the labs that I made. So, you could test
this yourself.
>> Uh, you can run the lab and then I'll
show you one of the labs. Maybe I'll
>> Yeah. While you're pulling that up, I
would like to ask you,
>> can you can you explain the difference
between um wildcard params and I I think
there's two ways of describing wild
cards, right? So, we've got, you know,
in our classic example about aboutxs
doctor, right? that XSS doctor is a
dynamic piece. I think they're called
dynamic parameters and wildcard
parameters or something like that. Can
you explain the difference of those and
how those are across different
frameworks?
>> The answer is actually uh something we
we didn't talk about is that basically
what is what is happening in each of
these functions is that it's building a
reax.
>> Mhm.
>> Whenever you have a dynamic parameter or
or a query parameter uh it it's
basically building a unique reax uh in a
particular way. So uh like the use
params is going to have one reax and
then the splat parameter is going to
have the splat the uh the wild card is
going to have another different reax and
the use params for example breaks on
slash whereas um like the splat
parameter it's just anything anything
you've put in between what you know in
that area is going to be taken exactly
that's not going to split on anything.
It's a dot star. That's that's what it
does in React, for example. It basically
slash dotstar slash. Okay. And it won't
differentiate.
>> So that's that's something I want to
make a little bit clearer for the
listener. So um let me see if I can find
it in the report while I'm talking about
it. But what what is the difference
between like where do we see
what what does a splat parameter look
like or a splat path look like in the
definition and what does its alternative
I guess a dynamic parameter look like?
Oh, so like a dynamic parameter. React's
a great example for all these things.
It's like it would be slash
colon user ID would be uh a regular
dynamic parameter
>> and then it would literally say like
slashfiles slashstar is a great example
>> um for a splat parameter because it um
it's like anything you put in there and
I think one of the reasons to do that is
uh they may have file names they may
have you know it may be different you
may want to capture the dot stuff like
that whereas um that's that's the reason
you do it often times that that was the
example I gave /filestar it's the most
vulnerable
code pattern okay in react
>> okay so two ways of of defining dynamic
path you have we're going to stick with
our same example about slashstar
and that will match about slxs
doctorc123
>> and and we've also got
um about slash colon username
>> or whatever right and that's right
>> and when we do that
>> if we put in something like about
slashinerator
then username gets populated as
reherator
>> but if we put about/rineratorc123
that abc123 is not put into username
just
>> or it doesn't match the route or or or
does it just populate by
>> depends what you're doing it depends how
you're doing it but if it if it's if
it's like slashfile/star you could put
anything in the world after that files
thing whereas if it's just the user ID
uh it depends I think uh for for for use
params for example you can't put a real
slash
>> it will it will be it will uh if that's
where it'll end um
you could put a percent 2F
>> even if you okay so let me ask you this
one splat plus no no splat isn't going
to end up in use params. So
>> correct, it's a different it's a
different path.
>> So if if they're using a splat route,
which is just about slash star and then
it's like anything after about just gets
put in there, but it doesn't get
populated as a parameter. It just Okay.
Okay. So one of these is a wildcard path
and one of these is a dynamic variable
in the path. Is that more accurate?
>> That's exactly that's exactly that's how
it's it was meant to be used. Yeah. And
they and that's that's how it's meant to
be used. And it it again it's all as
vulnerable as the developer wants it to
be. They could easily just take a splat
parameter and do save things with it.
Okay.
>> But it's harder to do that. That's a
really good that's a really good signal
piece for us though is is when there is
a splat parameter being or a splat path
defined right which is these star wild
card paths and we see them trying to
parse a a path parameter out of that
wildcard defined route splat splat route
so to speak. um then that is something
that should go ding ding ding ding ding
in our head like hey maybe we should
look into that a little bit more because
that's not how that's supposed to be
done.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Very good.
>> I'm going to I'm think what I'm going to
do is I'll just to show you this
differentiation I'll I'll um I'm going
to show you the lab. This is kind of how
I learned it and this helps this can
help you. So like let's say here right
this in this situation we're using use
params
and so what's happening here is that
this is what's the developer is actually
doing there's making a constant called
user ID and that equals use params and
that is running through this function
>> right
>> so it's taking this which is the user ID
which I've URL encoded and then it shows
what gets back so user ID equals the
decoded version
>> okay And then you could see that
I even fetched.
>> Yeah.
>> See, and then it's requesting this. So I
could even do my favorite
sett
>> by this he means it makes the request
that is constructed based on the decoded
username.
>> Yeah. And then you know and so this is
how I would do this. Um, now I even uh
where I put in three percent 2Fs and
then that's we're back at the
>> API secret endpoint. Okay. Yeah. So what
this this is a hands-on lab that is
demonstrating for those of you all uh
you know that you can traverse all using
use params the use the encoded path that
you set parameter that's set in via the
path gets pulled into a a variable via
use params that is decoded and when you
concatenate that with fetch it traverses
all the way back and one of your parts
of your flow uh JD is to um go all the
way back down to the document route. So
you can hit
>> Yeah. And then if you're if there's
something appended at the end, um you
know, you could put throw that in there
too, the hash. And then also if you see
the double URL encoded,
>> I threw the percent 252F. Now, what's
interesting that I found that I couldn't
figure out was a lowercase.
>> All right. I don't know.
>> Well, you've got 25 2F2F.
>> Oh, well anyway, the a lowercase 2F here
won't work
>> really. Yeah, if you do it like that,
you see?
>> Very odd. Oh, wow.
>> It's very odd, right?
>> Hey, that is a super good takeaway.
Whoa, I totally just got screwed on a
bunch of bugs then. Probably. So, what
you're saying is that percent 25 to F
lowercase functions differently than
percent 25 to f F uppercase.
>> And I cannot show up. Show me up.
>> You have to do it. We have to We have to
do it in a different window. You have to
do it in a different window. Uh because
if you do it in the same window. So,
wait.
It cached.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's why.
>> Add a cashbuster.
>> All right. I just do it like this
because I and I always preserve disable
cash. All right. So, we got this. So,
being percent 2F.
>> See?
>> Yep. Okay. So, on percent 25 to F. That
works, right? Wow.
>> Yeah. Whoa. But
>> then here the lower case, it doesn't
work.
>> Okay. Whoa. What? That That seems like
something. Are you sure that's not your
lab, bro?
>> I don't know, man. I don't understand
it. I could I couldn't figure it out
from the code either. So, it could be my
lab. I We have to kind of I I couldn't
figure it out.
>> But, I mean, your lab has got to be a
reflection of at least some production
system.
>> It's just doing this. Like, I don't
understand how that would do it. It's
literally just taking a vanilla modern
React and doing this and then and then
reflecting it. Dude, when we when we um
when we ship this research that needs to
be like bolded and at the top that is
like I have been screwed by that.
>> Tell us tell us why Justin tell us why.
>> Just Okay. Because like I of I'm only do
percent lowerase percent uh two
lowercase f. I have never capitalized in
f for I mean what he's saying
>> just because you're like typing it fast,
right? Like it's like you're just like
it's the same thing.
>> Me too. And then what what he's saying
here is that if you have a lowerase F,
it is not being decoded. In an uppercase
F, it is being decoded. What the [__]
>> But you should see that stuff, right?
Like we should be seeing that when we're
testing that it's not working. But I
guess we would just say it's not working
and double URL encoding is not working.
Yeah.
>> What the heck, dude?
>> It's weird, right?
>> Okay, I'm tripping a little bit. We're
going to have to
>> double like I my my app is extremely
simple, you know? It's just taking the
thing and so I I don't I can't imagine
that it's my app
>> because wow listeners I'm sorry I know
that we're kind of freaking out. Uh and
for those of you that are listening by
audio you probably don't have a lot a
big idea of what's going on here but
essentially what he just showed is that
in React use params which is one of the
most common ways I would say probably
the most common way to get path
parameters in single page applications
period. Uh I if you use percent 25 tof
lowercase it does not decode to slash
and if you use percent 252f uppercase f
it does. What the freak? Um
>> let's see let's see what it's like with
with with backslash.
>> Yeah. And a bunch of And you know what's
weird is
>> is Okay, dude. There's some sort of
caching. No, it's got to be some
caching, bro.
>> Well, what is that?
>> No, no, no, no, no. Wait, no. There
can't be. It didn't look like caching to
me. When I was watching JD redo it, it
looked completely
>> No, it's legit, man. It's freaking
legit.
>> It's legit. Yeah, I
>> But I don't understand why that's the
case.
>> Let's get demo. I mean, let's get Hold
on.
All right, we just summoned the the
client side, you know, conclave of mines
or whatever here to try to figure out
what happened here. And yeah, this is
legit. So, uh, excess doctor, dude, give
me some, man. Like, this is a very legit
finding. One of the best ones we've had
live on the pod, I think. Uh, but the
TLDDR of it, if as I understand, and you
can correct me if I'm wrong, is that the
reason why React double URL encoding
only decodes back to a slash for the
capital F in percent 25 to capital F is
because of this line right here, line
118 in match path. um I don't know the
name of the file in the source code but
it does a replace for percent to capital
F and swaps it to slash and it does not
do that in a case insensitive way. So
uppercase F will be mapped to this slash
and lowercase F will not be and that is
where the differential is occurring. Is
that correct? Yeah, and that actually
was put in after another double URL
encoding bug was reported to React like
as an issue, not as a as a bug bounty
bug. And they and this is how they fixed
it and they reintroduced this problem
and I guess made it like this.
>> Dude, I have missed so many CSPs because
of this. I never use a capital F. I will
always be using capital F now.
>> Yeah,
>> that's crazy.
>> Or maybe both. Or maybe you have to try
both in all these situations.
>> Another thing to try both on, man. It's
like, oh, here we go. But yeah, dude,
that is a zero day gadget in React
Router. That is uh super nuts. So, great
find. And uh
>> yeah, I'm glad we get to donate that to
the community.
>> There's a lot here. Like, there's way
more than I found, too. If you if you
just like look at any of these
frameworks and you look deeply into the
way that the routing happens, you're
going to find weird stuff that goes on.
I think just conceptually as well like
looking for replaces that are not case,
you know, insensitive is really good
idea.
Uh I think that there's a lot of
scenarios where that will slide past and
allow you to bypass something.
>> Um very cool, man. Well, we just got
super derailed and burnt a bunch of
time. Um Rezo, do you have to go or are
you good to stay for a little bit
longer?
>> Yeah, I I'll drop here in like a minute
or two, so you'll just see me drop off,
but
>> Okay. All right. Well, thanks for
joining us, man. Um, so we're getting
the rest of the path stuff. Uh, you
know, essentially you've outlined all of
the different frameworks here. So far,
we've talked about wild card or or um
split paths and actual dynamic paths.
That's good. Um, double URL encoding
happens in React Router, but everything
else does not. Um, and our fetch will
will automatically pull out, you know,
percent09 or tabs, uh, which helps with
Wi-Fi passes. Um
let's let's move unless you've got
anything else on path parameters. May
maybe we we talk a little bit more into
the server side rendering thing or
>> Yeah, that's interesting. Just quickly
on query parameters.
>> Yeah,
>> they're almost always decoded and that's
kind of how it should be. Yes,
>> like that, you know, that is what it is.
They it's it's a feature, not a bug. Uh
but if the query parameters pass to a
fetch, it's going to almost always lead
to um CSPT. Um or uh but the I think the
mo before we even went into this capital
lowerase app, the most interesting thing
I found on this in this research was
like I was looking for CSP, but there
are a bunch of these frameworks that are
that are hybrid or or server side and
those there's a risk of secondary path
reversal.
>> Yeah, secondary context path reversal
for sure. And and that's because the the
client side route is not encoding in the
in the back end. It is right just like
we talked about with the um with the
next situation. Was there anything else
that you wanted to cover there? I know
that there was some some pieces of like
um there's actual SSRF versus client
side or secondary context path
traversal. Where do we land on? and one
of the frameworks it bypasses like a
hook as well or something or I
>> I think the interesting the thing to
really focus on is when you're doing the
secondary context patch reversal it's
blind in the beginning right because
it's happening on the server as all
secondary context password is but in
something like react you're going to get
500s when you have stuff like that so
>> you should be testing in things like
spelt which are that not that much
written in spelt but uh and next you
should be doing putting these path
reversal payloads um to test for
secondary context path reversal, but you
should be doing the thing that was
spoken about uh on the pod with
secondary context path reversal where
you do the percent 2F let's say slash
settingss doctor percent 2f dot dot
percent2f xss doctor
>> yes
>> and and uh and that if that doesn't give
a 500
>> that is suggestive yes that you're
context
>> path normaliz you take a valid
valid value slash dot dot slash slash
uh you know
>> value valid value all right let me say
it one more time valid value slash dot
dot slash valid value
>> right
>> okay
>> and and basically you do invalid value
and you get 500 let's say
>> and then you do valid value and you
don't like next gives a lot of 500s
right uh if if you're messing up on the
back end
>> uh and that that's a nice takeaway of
that sort of research.
>> Excellent. Excellent, man. Um,
>> see you guys.
>> All right. Yeah, you're dropping. Peace,
Reszo. Um, all right. Well, that that
brings us through um sort of out of the
path related stuff. So, query parameters
almost all decoded, but you and I were
saying, you know, we do find more path
reversals in path parameters rather than
query parameters. I did want to bring up
a little bit of a interesting one,
though. You can get a sort of variant of
client side path traversals a little bit
more frequently in um quer parameters
where you're either injecting into a
part of the domain or you are in
injecting into a relative path where you
control the full relative path and it is
just
>> I know the target I know the target
you're talking about. I know the target
you're talking but that that's very
impactful when that happens when you're
injecting into a domain. uh it's
>> it's like a built-in uh open redirect as
well right so I guess do you have any
nomenclature you use for those sort of
scenarios or how do we ask like fetch
hijacking or
>> right no like what if what if the
beginning of the what if it's you're
injecting into
into the username and password part of
the URL so I you know because sometimes
they'll they don't realize you're doing
that and I'll use the same my favorite
website in hacking is the Portswigger
Academy URL parsing. What is it called?
A lab or something. Uh, pull that up
because it's the best. It is the
greatest thing ever to study this thing.
I use this
every day. I I'm obsessed with this for
a lot of a lot of reason. That thing.
Yeah. First, just study it like without
using it like this. just study it
because this will tell you everything
you need to know about about how URLs
are parsed um and about what you could
try to try different things and and I
I'll use this in that situation because
you don't like you're injecting into it
and you don't really know how it's being
handled or you have to figure it out and
you could do all these different cool
things.
>> Totally, dude. Yeah, this is a super
helpful cheat sheet and I really
appreciate that Port Swigger releases
this. Uh yeah there
>> and then another trick maybe I shouldn't
I is that I will every single time I'm
looking at ooth if you can inject into
that a username or password before the
at only if that is the case I will run
this entire list over that um that and
and I've found like a lot of bugs doing
that. Yeah. Yeah. Very common. Very
common. And now we know thanks to your
to your research today that we also need
to
>> upper and lower everything as well,
>> which is great. Love that for us.
>> So yeah, this is definitely a good cheat
sheet. We'll put it in the um we'll put
it in the description of the episode. Um
okay, awesome. So
that that is it largely for query. I I I
call that other that other variant um
fetch hijacking. I don't know if that's
the correct term or maybe like client
side request hijacking. Uh but then it
ch
or rh
it's a little off but um you know
hijacking a client side request that is
being sent uh pretty rare very impactful
typically when you can do it um if
you're injecting into the hosting
anywhere. I once got uh the only time
I've ever had uh web worker injection is
that
>> is that they were injecting into the
host name from a query parameter. I love
that.
>> I love that too, man. And then also um
it's so definitely the the query
parameter uh you know actually just
controlling the host name itself but
also if it's a relative path
>> and you gota that's one of the things
that won't pop up in network. So you got
to actually ch you in the network tab
you got to trace the sync or the source
um no trace the sync right where it's
actually sending the request put a you
know breakpoint right at the fetch
request and see what is being passed
into the fetch request because if
they're passing in a slash rather than
the full https colon whatever and you
can make it to slash or slbacks slash or
slash tab slash right all of that's
going to get resolved to slashes uh
which is going to allow it to become an
arbit arbitrary um you know an absolute
path rather than a uh relative path
>> and speaking of that it's actually
pretty hard sometimes to find those and
it's also very hard I find to find the
sync of the fetch where it's parsing the
JSON
>> that is I spend but if you guys if
whoever wants to get into client side
like do that a couple times and that
will help you with dynamic analysis a
lot cuz sometimes it's in a completely
separate place uh I don't know it's not
it's not always like fetch Then uh Jason
Jason pars like it like it's not that
easy.
>> They pass the promises around. It's like
oh
>> they're all over the place.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. One time I was looking at
something like that for like a day and
demoed found it in like 4 seconds.
>> Freaking hate that man.
>> And I'm like how did you find that? He's
like looking at the app.
>> Shut the freak up.
>> He's just one of those guys that uh just
has that like just you can just slurp it
all up. Him and Udyota are the two. And
dude, I'm so salty that Demo is lives
right up the street from me, too. I'm so
mad that he is in my city. Like, that
makes me so mad. Um, yeah.
>> Thank god nobody in Miami can hack.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. I'm just kidding. There
are some great If you're a great Miami
hacker, I apologize and call me. I'd
love to hack with you.
>> He'll really try to impress you. If you
submit a report first,
>> if you submit a report first, I'll go
crazy. Dude, you know what would be like
the best troll ever would be to like
say, "Hey, exist. Do you want to like do
full collab on this like, you know,
target and then but secretly you've been
working on it for 3 weeks beforehand and
you have like 10 bucks?"
>> And then and then as soon as they're
like, "Oh, I found one. I found one."
It'll cost you a couple grand, but it'll
drive JD nuts,
>> you know? Like,
>> and how'd you find that looking at the
app?
>> Yeah, looking at the app.
>> Just looking I just looked at it. Did
you Did you Didn't look at it cuz I
looked at it.
>> Yeah. JD, could you like spend more time
hacking? I feel like, oh my gosh. Um,
all right. Last piece of of stuff from
this uh research that I'd like to go
over is uh the
custom syncs that uh you know incur
fetch requests to be made in the various
frameworks. So I'm going to go ahead and
share my screen again. Can you talk a
little bit about those that you
discovered in various frameworks? So I
mean there there are actually others uh
this was like uh like that are a little
bit more like like I keep talking about
demo turbo he did has wonderful research
in react xss syncs that I did not
include here because that's his research
but the like the most basic ones are
dangerous set inner html for react and
next shares that in view and nux there's
something called a v d-hl
which is similar angular uses um this
bypass secure for security trust HTML.
>> Um, spelt kit has just curly braces.
>> So, there's a bunch of different ways to
get HTML triggered in all the various
frameworks. And I think that that is
certainly it's nice to have this list at
the end, right? That you that you
included at the end. But what I'm
talking about more is this guy um this
guy right here, the URL for find record.
So, this is a built-in version of fetch
essentially, right? Like fetch is
powering.
>> You're talking about syncs. You're
you're talking about the sinks. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Is that
>> Yeah, that's it. Yeah, that's that's
basically the whole thing, but yeah,
it's very interesting. There's a couple
of those, but that's that's the most uh
that's the most the most prominent one
where they like wrap something around
fetch that makes it more vulnerable.
>> Okay, so explain this one for me. So, an
ember you obviously you can use fetch,
right? But then there's also a built-in
utility that you see them using a lot of
times that also is not doing um
traversal even though you're passing in
see what seems weird to me here right is
you're passing into this ID and model
name or whatever right
>> and it's actually like so you're not
it's not like you're passing in a URL
you are passing in it's almost like the
interpolation thing that we we said we
wanted right but then they're just not
sanitizing it right
>> exactly right yeah they they're
introducing They're basically
introducing a bug this way in in this
custom way. It's very it's very
interesting behavior.
>> Okay. And this is an ember and and is it
always URL for find record or is there a
different structure?
>> No, that's it. That's what the function
is called.
>> Okay. All right. And yeah, I think this
is a really good thing to keep looking
for in other frameworks is like when
I'm, you know, scrolling through the
code, when I see URL for find record,
um, you know, I'm not necessarily
thinking, oh, this is going to be
vulnerable, right? But uh this guy right
here will be creating these you know
URLs that uh will be then passed to
fetch and it was doing the string
interpolation but it's not actually
encoding any of the values itself.
>> And that's another thing to think about
too is that there's another sync that I
didn't even talk about here which is the
server.
>> The server may normalize URL encoded and
that that's very common. uh the API
itself will point.
>> Yeah. So um I always that's actually
usually the first thing I test because
then you don't have to think about this.
>> Then it gets passed to fetch fetch do
whatever it wants and the back end is
going to URL decode for you.
>> Yeah.
>> Um then you could triple URL encodes
react.
>> Oh my gosh, we're getting into crazy
layers here. Triple URL encode and Yeah.
And then also sometimes, you know, if
you can smuggle in a a percent 3f or
something like that in those sort of
environments, that's a really strong
signal. You know, if it if it's taking
your percent 2F, it's still processing
it as a path separator. Very strong
signal for um for cash poisoning.
>> Um very much so.
>> And it would be hard for W to get all
these.
>> Oh, yeah, for sure.
>> Yeah. I mean, there's there's too much
variation.
>> Yeah. All right. Well, if you guys
haven't uh seen the value already of
reading this write up by XSS doctor that
will be on lab.ctb.show,
then uh you're crazy. Uh so definitely
go read it. Read it thoroughly. Uh and
I'm not going to lie to you guys. I sat
down and it took me a long time to get
through it, even as somebody who's, you
know, proficient with client side stuff.
But the value that I got out of just
reading this is very, very high. And I
think you guys will as well.
>> And do the labs. the labs is is even
more important because if you do the
labs with it, you'll you'll like play
with it and you'll find stuff I didn't
find, you know, with with those labs.
You do weird stuff to the parameters and
see what you get.
>> Yes, totally. Um, dude, thank you so
much for for coming on and for dazzling
us with all of this. Uh, it was awesome.
And yeah,
>> it's the Price is Right. I am on the
Price is Right right now and I am a
contestant. I'm that excited. I like
those people on that show.
>> Awesome, man. Well, well, Gigi, let's
get back to the hacking itself then.
Yeah.
All right. Peace. That's the pod.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.